instabug.com 2019-12-24

# Instabug Privacy Policy | Instabug

###  Introduction 

By using the www.instabug.com website (“ **Site** ”) and any related services and/or features (together with the Site, the " **Service** ") you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or our use of your data, please contact us at privacy@instabug.com 

###  Scope 

This Privacy Policy covers Instabug's treatment of personal data ("Personal Data") that Instabug gathers when you access or otherwise use the Service. It explains what data we collect, why we collect the data, how it is used and your rights and choices. While providing our Service, we may collect information about our customers’ users on behalf of our customers. Our use of this information is governed by our agreement with the applicable customer and the customer’s own privacy policies. We does not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies or privacy practices of our customers or any other third parties. 

While providing our Service, we may collect information about our customers’ users on behalf of our customers. Our use of this information is governed by our agreement with the applicable customer and the customer’s own privacy policies. We does not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies or privacy practices of our customers or any other third parties. 

###  1- What Personal Data does Instabug collect? 

**Information That You Provide To Us**. Instabug collects information you voluntarily submit to the Service when you register for an account: your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, payment related information (credit card number, physical address, etc.). We also collect Personal Data that is entered on our Site or is sent to us electronically when you request information, including a product demo, register for a webinar or other event, complete any “free text” boxes in our forms (for example, support request or survey submission). In addition, we may collect Personal Data disclosed by you on our forums, blogs and our other areas of the Service to which you can post information and materials. 

**Information Received From Third-Party Services** . If you connect to the Service using credentials from a third party service or sign-in services such as OAuth (for example, login with a GitHub or Google account), these services will authenticate a user’s identity and provide the user with the option to share certain Personal Data, such as name and email address(es), with us. 

**Automatically Collected Data** . Whenever you interact with the Service, we automatically receive and store certain types of information including information that your browser automatically sends. Such information may include the user's IP address (from which we understand the country you are connecting from at the time you visit the Site), domain server, and type of Internet browser. 

We also use "cookies" (small text files placed on your device) and similar technologies to operate the Service, track your experience and use of the Service and to present you with advertising relevant to your interests. You can read more about how we use cookies and similar technologies on our  Cookie Policy . 

###  2\. How does Instabug use the information it collects? 

\- **Provide the Service** : Your Personal Data will be used primarily to provide you with the Service, contact you regarding your access and use of the Service and/or the Site or to notify you of important changes to the Service. Such use is necessary for the performance of the contract between you and us. 

\- **For certain legitimate business purposes** : 

· improve the Service and develop new products, services and features ; 

· to send administrative information to you, for example, information regarding the Site and changes to  our terms, conditions , and policies; 

· to respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to send you requested information or materials; 

· to prevent fraud or criminal activity, misuses of our products or services, and ensure the security of our IT systems, architecture and networks; 

· if you ask us to delete your data and we are required to fulfil your request, to keep basic data to identify you and prevent further unwanted processing; 

· to (a) comply with legal obligations and legal process, (b) respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (c) enforce  our terms and conditions  ; (d) protect our operations; (e) protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of you or others; and (f) allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

\- **Marketing** . We may use your contact details to tell you about services we believe will be of interest to you, upcoming events or other promotions. If we do so, each marketing communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt out" of receiving future marketing communications. Note however that as user of our services you cannot opt out of some administrative communications that are reasonably necessary to the Service, such as billing or service notifications. In addition, if at any time you wish not to receive any future marketing communications or you wish to have your name deleted from our mailing lists, please contact us as indicated below. 

Where required by applicable law (for example, if you are an individual in the EU), we will only send you marketing information by email if you consent to us doing so at the time you provide us with your Personal Data. When you provide us with your consent to be contacted for marketing purposes, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by following the instructions to “opt-out” of receiving marketing communication in each marketing email we send you or by contacting us as indicated below. 

###  3\. Will Instabug share any of the personal data it receives? 

Instabug only shares Personal Data with other companies or individuals outside of Instabug in the following circumstances: 

\- You've shared your information as a result of giving feedback within an application using the Service. We only share this information with the developer of the application, in order to assist you and the developer in communicating. 

\- Instabug, like many businesses, sometimes hires other companies to perform certain business-related functions: website analytics companies, providers of digital advertising services, our hosting and cloud computing service providers, providers of CRM, marketing and sales software solutions, providers of billing and processing payments functions . When we employ another company to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function. Pursuant to our instructions, these parties may access, process or store Personal Data in the course of performing their duties to us and solely in order to perform the services we have hired them to provide. 

\- Protection of Instabug and Others: We may release Personal Data when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with the law; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Instabug, our employees, our users, or others. 

\- Business Transfers: If Instabug, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Instabug goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, Personal Data about our customers would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Instabug may continue to use your Personal Data as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

\- With Your Consent: Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Data may be shared with third parties, and will be able to prevent the sharing of this information pursuant to the applicable law. 

###  4\. European Union (EU) Users 

**Scope** . This section applies if you are a user in the EU (for these purposes, reference to the EU also includes the European Economic Area countries of Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway). 

**Data Controller** . Instabug, Inc. is the data controller for processing Personal Data provided to us through the Service. To find out our registered office, please see the “Contact Us” section below. 

**Your Rights** . Subject to applicable law, you have the following rights in relation to your Personal Data: 

•

 **Right of access** : If you ask us, we will confirm whether we are processing your Personal Data and, if so, provide you with a copy of that Personal Data along with certain other details. If you require additional copies, we may need to charge a reasonable fee. 

•

 **Right to rectification** : If your Personal Data is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to ask that we correct or complete it. If we shared your Personal Data with others, we will tell them about the correction where possible. If you ask us, and where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you with whom we shared your Personal Data so you can contact them directly. 

•

 **Right to erasure** : You may ask us to delete or remove your Personal Data, such as where you withdraw your consent. If we shared your data with others, we will tell them about the erasure where possible. If you ask us, and where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you with whom we shared your Personal Data with so you can contact them directly. 

•

 **Right to restrict processing** : You may ask us to restrict or ‘block’ the processing of your Personal Data in certain circumstances, such as where you contest the accuracy of the data or object to us processing it (please read below for information on your right to object). We will tell you before we lift any restriction on processing. If we shared your Personal Data with others, we will tell them about the restriction where possible. If you ask us, and where possible and lawful to do so, we will also tell you with whom we shared your Personal Data so you can contact them directly. 

•

 **Right to data portability** : You have the right to obtain your Personal Data from us that you consented to give us or that was provided to us as necessary in connection with our contract with you. We will give you your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. You may reuse it elsewhere. 

•

 **Right to object** : You may ask us at any time to stop processing your Personal Data, and we will do so: 

-

If we are relying on a legitimate interest to process your Personal Data -- unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing or 

-

If we are processing your Personal Data for direct marketing. 

•

 **Right to withdraw consent** : If we rely on your consent to process your Personal Data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal of consent will not affect any processing of your data before we received notice that you wished to withdraw consent. 

•

 **Right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority** : If you have a concern about our privacy practices, including the way we handled your Personal Data, you can report it to the data protection authority that is authorized to hear those concerns. You can find [ here ](https://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080) the contact details of EU data protection authorities. 

**Legitimate Interest** . “Legitimate interests” means our interests in conducting our business, managing and delivering the best Service to you. This Privacy Policy describes when we process your Personal Data for our legitimate interests, what these interests are and your rights. We will not use your Personal Data for activities where the impact on you overrides our interests, unless we have your consent or those activities are otherwise required or permitted to by law. 

###  5\. Data Retention 

We will keep your Personal Data for as long as reasonably necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, while we have a legitimate business need to do so, or as required by law (e.g. for tax, legal, accounting or other purposes), whichever is the longer. 

If you have elected to receive marketing communications from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences until you opt out of receiving these communications and in accordance with our policies. 

To determine the appropriate retention period for your Personal Data, we will consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the Personal Data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your Personal Data, the purposes for which we use your Personal Data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements. In some circumstances we may anonymize your Personal Data so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case it is no longer Personal Data. 

###  6\. International Users 

Instabug is based in the United States. If you are accessing our Service from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that your Personal Data will be transmitted to our servers in the United States and the data may be transmitted to our service providers supporting our business operations (described above). The United States may have data protection laws less stringent than or otherwise different from the laws in effect in the country in which you are located. Where we transfer your Personal Data out of the EU we will take steps to ensure that your Personal Data receives an adequate level of protection where it is processed and your rights continue to be protected. For information that we process on behalf of our customers, we have implemented appropriate contractual provisions (including, for data collected from the EU, standard contractual clauses for data transfers) to ensure adequate protections for your Personal Data. Please contact us if you have any questions on the safeguards that we implement when we transfer your Personal Data. 

###  7\. Conditions of Use 

If you decide to access or use the Service, such access and use and any possible dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Policy and our  Terms of Use , including limitations on damages and disclaimer of warranties to the extent permitted by the applicable law. 

###  8\. Third Party Website/Services 

The Site may permit you to link to other websites on the Internet, and other websites may contain links to the Site. These other websites are not under Instabug control, and by providing these links we do not imply that we endorse or have reviewed these other websites or the services offered through them. The information that you share with such websites will be governed by the specific privacy policies and terms of service of the third party websites and not by this Privacy Policy. Instabug is not responsible for the privacy or security practices or the content of such websites. 

###  9\. Information Security 

We take care to protect your Personal Data against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction, through appropriate security measures. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, including encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store Personal Data. 

###  10\. Changes to this Privacy Policy 

Instabug may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make changes in the way we use Personal Data, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our Site, or via the Service, or sending you an email. Users are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Service after such changes have been first posted.
